#### **BIODATA**

Name: Kennedy Murimi Wachira

Date of birth: Wednesday, August 7, 1991

Gender: Male

Nationality: Kenyan

Contacts: Mobile: +254704 103 356

Email: murimi.kenn@gmail.com

Portfolio: <a href="https://creativekenn.netlify.app">https://creativekenn.netlify.app</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/kenndev">https://github.com/kenndev</a>

#### **CAREER AND PERSONAL SUMMARY**

I am a brilliant and prolific full-stack software developer. I have been coding professionally for seven years now, enjoying every minute of it, and learning multiple new tools and technologies. I'm familiar with working within multidisciplinary teams, on complex projects, and can be counted on to stay calm under pressure and deliver quality work. I've got a knack for solving problems efficiently and am always looking for ways to provide efficiencies that will save time later in the development process.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Global Tech Network: (Orlando, Florida, United States)

2022 to date: Full-Stack Developer

### **Duties and responsibilities**

- ✓ Plan, design, and execute end-to-end web architecture.
- ✓ Collaborate with interdisciplinary teams to deliver high-quality products.
- ✓ Build scalable, responsive, and high-performant stacks.
- ✓ Stay on top of trends and apply that to get the best of systems and the team.
- ✓ Analyze requirements to design, document, estimate, and build new and existing system features.
- Maintain and improve the code quality, stability, maintainability, and support.
- ✓ Develop production-ready code, tests, and participate in code reviews.
- ✓ Develop, improve, and maintain web and cross platform mobile applications.

# Design Lab Technologies Limited: (Nairobi, Kenya)

2015 to 2022: Full-Stack Developer

## **Duties and responsibilities**

- ✓ Design, develop and expose different services as Application Programming Interface (APIs).
- ✓ Supporting sales team to identify new opportunities in product /service offerings and provide technical knowledge on payments.
- ✓ Working closely with the business team and product managers by providing technical feasibility, proof of concepts, innovations, demos for end to end payment simulations and strategies to reach new market.
- ✓ Ensuring technical queries and incidents are resolved within relevant SLAs and to a high standard.
- ✓ Issues troubleshooting and resolution, escalations to relevant support teams.
- ✓ Designing of the projects interfaces.
- ✓ Leading a team of developers in coding the projects.
- ✓ Deploying of projects and regular updates in platforms such as Heroku, AWS, Digital Ocean, and Netlify.

# Coleman Technologies: (Nairobi, Kenya)

2014: Junior Developer

### **Duties and responsibilities**

- ✓ Getting customer requirements for projects and coming up with the user interface of the applications.
- ✓ Developing Card Payment Service, REST API, through integration with MasterCard Payment Gateway Service running on Azure cloud.
- ✓ Support and troubleshoot test and production issues.
- ✓ Promoting best practices, in terms of development tools, technologies and testing within the team.
- ✓ Review and validation of ongoing system analysis and design of software projects.
- ✓ Leading a team of developers in designing and coding of the projects.
- ✓ Database design and implementation.

✓ Organize and lead technical workshops with both product managers and other technical teams to streamline activities.

Ministry of Education: (Nairobi, Kenya)

2013: Internship

Achievements

✓ Took part in implementation, testing, and maintenance of a system that would form

the backbone of the ministry's working.

✓ Maintained the ministry's servers and made sure they were always online available

and reliable

✓ Set up new network connections and configurations within the ministry

✓ Staff IT support, mainly involved helping the staff with their daily issues such as

network connectivity, problems with using the operating systems, and printer

settings problems.

Gigatech Technologies: (Nairobi, Kenya)

2012: IT Technician and Network Administrator

**Duties and responsibilities** 

✓ Worked as an I.T consultant and maintained networks.

✓ Hardware repairs for computers and computer accessories.

✓ Helped the sales team in selling computers, laptops and computer accessories.

**KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

Frameworks: Laravel, Vue.js, React, Django

SCM/Version Control Tools: Git

Container Technologies: Docker, Kubernetes

**SDLC:** Agile, SCRUM

Ticketing/Bug Tracking: Jira

Database Systems: PostgreSQL, MySQL

Languages: PHP, Java, C, JavaScript, Python, dart

**Mobile Application Development:** Cross platform apps using Flutter

Cloud Services: Heroku, Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, Digital Ocean, Netlify.

### **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

# **Bachelor of Science Computer Science**

Kenyatta University; September 2010 – December 2014.

## **Certificate in Mobile Application Development**

Google Mobile Application Development Boot Camp, Kenyatta University; April 2013 – August 2013.

## Cisco Certified Network Associate, CCNA

Computer Pride; June 2012 – August 2012.

# **Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (K.C.S.E)**

Nyeri High School; 2006 – 2009.

### **REFEREES**

#### **Phaustine Namsenda**

Software Engineer, Microsoft

pnapunyi@gmail.com

+254716191832

# **Victor Mochengo**

Senior Data Scientist, Asante Financial Services Group

victormochengo@gmail.com

+254723649624

# Samuel Gichuki

**CEO Linsure Insurance Limited** 

sam.gichuki@linsure.co.ke

+254721361360